Frank Ormsby papers, circa 1967-2004
Emory University
- Writings by Frank Ormsby, 1970-1995, Series 3; Boxes 17-29; OP6-9, 20
  - Poetry by Frank Ormsby, 1970-1995, Subseries 3.1; Boxes 17-22
    - Uncollected poetry, 1970-1995, Subseries 3.1c; Box 20: folder 8 - Box 22
      - "Weightlifter," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 90)
      - "The Well," TS [circa pre-1971] (Box 22, Folder 91)
      - "Well-Wisher," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 92)
      - "West Chlorine Gardens," TS [variant title: "Interior Summer"] (Box 22, Folder 93)
      - "Wet Day," TS (Box 22, Folder 94)
      - "A Wet Hour in Belfast," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 95)
      - "Where Are They Now?" MS (Box 22, Folder 96)
      - "Whereabouts," MS (Box 22, Folder 97)
      - "Windsor Park," MS, TS [variant title: "Near Windsor Park"] (Box 22, Folder 98)
      - "Windy Day," MS [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Derrycullen Churchyard" for MS]
      - "Winter in the City," MS, TS (Box 22, Folder 99)
      - "Woman and Child," TS [circa pre-1971] (Box 22, Folder 100)
      - "The Woodcutter's Daughter," MS [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "Well-Wisher" for TS] (Box 22, Folder 101)
      - "Woodland, Near a Manor," TS (Box 22, Folder 102)
      - "Words," MS (Box 22, Folder 103)
      - "Working Days," TS [includes: "Continuities I," "The Cleaning Ladies," "Masters," "The Unemployed," "Loading and Unloading," "Continuities II"] (Box 22, Folder 104)
      - "Working on the Railway," TS [includes: "Arts and Crafts" and "Angel Cake"] (Box 22, Folder 105)
      - "The Wrong Funeral," MS (Box 22, Folder 106)
      - "Wrong Numbers," MS, TS [variant titles: "The Samaritans," "Emergency Calls"] (Box 22, Folder 107)
      - "The Young Man Discusses His Mother," MS [circa 1970-1977] (Box 22, Folder 108)
      - Untitled manuscript fragments 1970-1978 (Box 22, Folder 109)
      - Untitled manuscript fragments 1981-1982 (Box 22, Folder 110)
      - Untitled manuscript fragments 1983-1987 (Box 22, Folder 111)
      - Untitled manuscript fragments 1989-1994 (Box 22, Folder 112)
      - Untitled typescript fragments circa pre-1971 (Box 22, Folder 113)
      - Untitled typescript fragments circa 1970-1977 (Box 22, Folder 114)
  - Prose by Frank Ormsby, 1966-1995, Subseries 3.2; Box 23; OP 6
    As a prose writer, Ormsby produced works of fiction and autobiography, as well as book reviews, critical essays, speeches, and interviews. Notes describe specific documents with varying levels of detail, including date of composition and/or eventual publication. Many reviews and essays remain untitled, though most descriptions of such texts refer to the reviewed text or other salient details.
    Ormsby's prose is collected in subsections pertaining to fiction, autobiography, book reviews, essays, speeches, and interviews. Individual texts are listed alphabetically by title under each subsection. Untitled reviews are listed alphabetically by the author under consideration.
    - Fiction
    - Journal of holiday in Turkey (1989) with part of novel written there but later abandoned (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Relief! Relief! TS novel, circa 1966 [written while Ormsby was a pupil at St. Michael's College, Enniskillen] (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Untitled, TS novel fragments, circa 1968 [written while Ormsby was an undergraduate at Queen's University Belfast] (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Autobiography
    - "Winter Journal I," MS [uncollected] (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - "Winter Journal II," MS [uncollected] (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - "Winter Journal Extras," MS [uncollected] (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Reviews
    - "Heaney's ‘Voices,' Raine's ‘Riches,'" MS review of Seamus Heaney's Station Island (1984) and Craig Raine's Rich (1984) [See also Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby, "Heaney's ‘Voices,' Raine's ‘Riches'"] (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - "John Hewitt's ‘Chosen Ground,'" MS draft of review of John Hewitt's The Day of the Corncrake: Poems of the Nine Glens, for unknown, undated newspaper [See also Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby, "John Hewitt's ‘Chosen Ground'"] (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - "A Journey Back," MS draft of review of Roy McFadden's After Seymour's Funeral (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - "Longley: Chapter and Verse," MS review of Michael Longley's Poems: 1963-1983 [See also Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby, "Longley: Chapter and Verse"] (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - "Personal Gestures," galley proof of review of Kinsella's The New Oxford Book of Irish Verse and Muldoon's The Faber Book of Contemporary Irish Poetry, in The Times Educational Supplement, 11 July 1986 [See also Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby, "Personal Gestures"] (Box OP6)
    - "The Short Stories of James Plunkett," TS review of The Trusting and the Maimed by James Plunkett (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - "Ulster Poet Waxing Lyrical on Debut," MS review of Peter McDonald's Biting the Wax (1990) [published in Belfast Telegraph, 18 July 1990] (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Untitled, MS review of John Broderick's An Apology for Roses (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Untitled, MS review of Gerald Dawe's Sunday School (1991) (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Untitled, MS review of Paul Durcan's Going Home to Russia (1987) (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Untitled, MS review of Gavin Ewart's unknown volume (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Untitled, MS review of Robert Johnston's All Shy Wildness (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Untitled, MS essay on Louis MacNeice's Autumn Journal (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Untitled, MS review of James Simmons' From the Irish (1985) (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Miscellaneous MS notes for reviews (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Essays
    - "Coping," MS [essay on the Northern Ireland Troubles] (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - "Local Promptings," MS draft of essay on A Northern Spring for PBS Bulletin, 1986 [See also Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby, "Local Promptings"] (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - "The Long Embrace," MS, TS, used as basis for BBC Northern Ireland, Radio Ulster script [See also Subseries 3.4: Scripts by Ormsby, "The Long Embrace"] (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - "Obituary: George Buchanan," MS, TS for London Times (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - "Tomorrow with His Notes," MS draft of essay / lecture delivered at the John Hewitt International Summer School [later published] (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Untitled MS, diary of trip to Romania 1-10 October 1987 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Untitled MS, TS essay on Irish poetry and painting (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Untitled MS, explications of poems from Ormsby's A Store of Candles (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Untitled, notes about Ulster violence, MS (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Speeches
    - "The Prizewinners," TS [speech for Ulster awards summer] (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - Untitled TS speech at unknown secondary school's prize night (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - Untitled TS speech / talking points at poetry reading of A Northern Spring materials (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - Interviews
    - Interview of Frank Ormsby by Patricia Horton, 3 April 1995 [includes original interview notes, revisions, final draft] (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - Scripts by Frank Ormsby, 1970-1989, Subseries 3.3; Box 24: folders 1-11
    Across his career, Ormsby has been involved with literary programs written and presented for radio audiences. His various scripts are arranged chronologically by either the recording date or the transmission date. In some cases, Ormsby read parts himself. Most scripts were prepared for BBC Northern Ireland.
    Arranged in chronological order.
    - "Soundings," TS, transmission: 6 September 1970, BBC Northern Ireland, Radio Ulster (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - "Words Alone I," TS, transmission: 3 January 1971, BBC Northern Ireland, Radio Ulster [Compilation by Michael Longley; Ormsby reads "Gypsies"] (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - "Prospect," TS, transmission: 4 January 1972, BBC Northern Ireland, Radio Ulster (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - "Three Days in Lourdes," MS, TS, transmission: 9 July 1978, BBC Northern Ireland, Radio Ulster (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - "Meet the Divine Amanda," MS, TS, transmission: 12 February 1988, BBC Northern Ireland, Radio Ulster (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - "The Long Embrace," TS, transmission: 14 February 1988, BBC Northern Ireland, Radio Ulster, [includes correspondence from producer] [See also Subseries 3.2: Prose by Ormsby (essays), "The Long Embrace"] (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - "Sketches of Britain," TS, transmission: 20 February 1988, BBC Northern Ireland, Radio Ulster (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - "Poets in Person: Frank Ormsby," TS, recorded: 25 June 1988, BBC Northern Ireland, Radio Ulster (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - "Explorations / Love," TS, recorded: 17 March 1989, BBC Northern Ireland, Radio Ulster (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - "Today & Yesterday in Northern Ireland: Setanta," TS, transmission: 16 August 1989, BBC Northern Ireland, Radio Ulster (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Untitled, TS, undated [includes: gypsy characters, Ormsby as narrator] (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Works edited by Frank Ormsby, 1979-1992, Subseries 3.4; Box 24: folders 12-23 - Box 29; OP 7-9, 20
    In addition to his career as a poet, a writer of critical prose, and a magazine editor, Ormsby is noteworthy for his role in editing some very important anthologies or highly researched editions of single authors' works. Ormsby's Poets from the North of Ireland and A Rage for Order: Poetry of the Northern Ireland Troubles have proven to be both critically acclaimed and widely used poetry anthologies. His edition of the Belfast poet John Hewitt's Collected Poems has proven to be similarly valuable.
    The correspondence related to the production of specific books is separately collected in the project correspondence subseries (1.2). Similarly, printed material (reviews and promotional materials) pertaining to specific volumes is arranged by book in the printed material subseries (5.2).
    Materials in this subseries are arranged chronologically by volume. Each book's subsection contains distinct items relevant to its production, though many of the books offer drafts of research material or bibliographies, introductions, and collections of primary, mostly photocopied documents.
    - Poets from the North of Ireland (1979, 1991)
    - Poets from the North of Ireland (1991), bibliographies (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Poets from the North of Ireland (1991), table of contents (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Poets from the North of Ireland (1979), Introduction (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Poets from the North of Ireland (1991), Introduction (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Poets from the North of Ireland (1979), Index (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Poets from the North of Ireland (1991), Index (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Galley proofs [photocopies] (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Jacket cover [proof, photocopy] (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - The Long Embrace: Twentieth Century Irish Love Poems (1987)
    - Permissions (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Tables of contents, MS, TS (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - "Foreword," MS, TS (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - "The Long Embrace," TS essay for BBC Northern Ireland's Radio Talk, 19 February 1988 [See also Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby, "Long Embrace"] (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Northern Windows: An Anthology of Ulster Autobiography (1987)
    - Bibliographies (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Permissions (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Tables of Contents, MS, TS (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Biographical notes (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Introduction, MS, TS (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Research materials No. 1 [photocopies of prose not included in the book] (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Research materials No. 2 [photocopies of prose not included in the book] (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Research materials No. 3 [photocopies of prose not included in the book] (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Thine in Storm and Calm: An Amanda McKittrick Ros Reader (1988)
    - Bibliographies (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Permissions (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Reviews and Criticism of McKittrick (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Editor's notes, MS, TS (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - "Introduction," MS, TS (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Research materials: assorted prose, MS and photocopies (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Research materials: assorted poetry, MS and photocopies (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Research materials: assorted correspondence, MS and photocopies (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Research materials: correspondence from McKittrick, Denis Johnston, and George Shields [1903-1948], photocopies (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Tables of Contents, MS (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - "Irene Iddesleigh," TS and photocopies (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - "Delina Delaney," TS and photocopies (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - "Helen Huddleson," TS and photocopies (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - "The Poems," TS and photocopies (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - "Some Letters," TS and photocopies (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - The Collected Poems of John Hewitt (1991)
    - Biographical materials (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Biographical and Informational articles about Hewitt [includes memorial pieces and obituaries] (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - "Preface," MS (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - "Introduction," MS (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Bibliographic research materials (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Bibliography, "The Prose Writings of John Hewitt: A Bibliography, With an Introduction and an Appendix, Comprising a Selection of his Works," (1985) by Tom Clyde [incomplete photocopy] (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Bibliography of Hewitt contributions to The Bell (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Personal Correspondence of Hewitt [assorted letters] (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Poetry by Hewitt: untitled MS poem on Christmas card (1968) [dedicated to Busha] (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Poetry by Hewitt: broadsheet [includes: "I write for--," "On a January Train," "Skypiece"] (Box OP20)
    - Poetry by Hewitt: notebook 1933-1938 [assorted unpublished and published poems photocopied from a journal/journals] (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Poetry by Hewitt: notebook 1940-1943 [assorted unpublished and published poems photocopied from a journal/journals] (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Poetry by Hewitt: Conacre: A Poem (1943) [photocopy] (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Poetry by Hewitt: from Tesserae (1967) [photocopy] (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Poetry by Hewitt: from The Day of the Corncrake (1969) [photocopy] (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Poetry by Hewitt: from The Planter and the Gael (1967) [photocopy] (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Poetry by Hewitt: assorted poems [photocopies] (Box OP7)
    - Poetry by Hewitt: poems from The Bell [photocopies] (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Poetry by Hewitt: poems from The New Northman [photocopies] (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Poetry by Hewitt: assorted poems and fragments [photocopies] (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Poetry by Hewitt: assorted poems I [photocopies] (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Poetry by Hewitt: assorted poems II [photocopies] (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Poetry by Hewitt: assorted poems III [photocopies] (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Poetry by Hewitt: assorted poems [clippings] (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - Poetry by Hewitt: index of first lines and bibliography [notecards] (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Prose by Hewitt: assorted essays and reviews [photocopies] (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Prose by Hewitt: assorted essays and reviews [photocopies] (Box OP8)
    - Prose by Hewitt: essays and reviews from The Bell [photocopies] (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Prose by Hewitt: essays and reviews from The New Northman [photocopies] (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Prose by Hewitt: "Planter's Gothic," autobiographies from The Bell [photocopies] (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Prose by Hewitt: "Report by the Art Director on his Visit to Poland, 7-12 June 1962," TS [photocopy] (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Prose by Hewitt: short stories from The Bell [photocopies] (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Prose by Hewitt: radio scripts (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Prose by Hewitt: assorted interviews and conversations [photocopies] (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Prose by Hewitt: interviews and conversations from The Bell [photocopies] (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Prose by Hewitt: interview ["The Doyen"] in Quarto Literary Magazine, 1980-1981 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Essays about Hewitt and his work (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Reviews of Hewitt's books (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Reviews of Hewitt's books (Box OP9)
    - Reviews of Hewitt's books in The Bell [photocopies] (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Programs and brochures (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Photographs (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - A Rage for Order: Poetry of the Northern Ireland Troubles (1992)
    - Lists of contributors' poems under consideration, MS (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Table of contents, MS (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Assorted poems, TS [collected] (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Assorted poems, TS [uncollected and unattributed] (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Foreword, TS (Box 29, Folder 20)
- Writings by others, circa 1971-1972, Series 4; Box 30: folders 1-8
  The poetry and prose writing by others collected here represents unpublished material that has been sent personally to Ormsby. As editor of The Honest Ulsterman, most of the unpublished writing sent to him was submitted for publication, and all such manuscript and typescript drafts are kept in The Honest Ulsterman submissions subseries. Most of the items in the writings by others series are actually worksheets from sessions of the Belfast Group attended by Ormsby during the 1971-1972 academic year.
  - Poetry
  - Dugdale, Norman: Belfast Group worksheet, circa 1972 [includes poems: Terminus, A Question of Identity, A Self-Portrait, Salmon-Leap: Mayo, On a Recent Happy Event, Saturday, N.W.S., Autopsy on the Fifth Decade] (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Heaney, Seamus: "The Tollund Man," [photocopy of TS with Ormsby's MS fragments on verso; dated November 1974] (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - MacLaverty, Bernard: Belfast Group worksheet, 30 November 1971 [includes the short story: St. Paul Could Hit the Nail on the Head] (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - MacLaverty, Bernard: Belfast Group worksheet, 14 February 1972 [includes the short story: The Deep End] (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - McGurk, Tom: Belfast Group worksheet, circa 1971-1972 [includes poems: September Sibelius, Protest, The Son of the King of Moy, Apologia in Memoriam, Greetings, Mise Eire, Facts of Life] (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - McMahon, Trevor: Belfast Group worksheet, 22 November 1971 [includes poems: Moth, Worm, The Planter Speaks, Old Man, To Those Involved in Rigid Disciplines, Rat Song, The Fool's Soliloquy, Poem as Mammoth] (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - O'Canainn, Thomas: Kindling, TS [undated collection of poems] (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Prose
  - Egan, Neil: "Above Electrolux the Moon," TS (Box 30, Folder 8)
- Printed material, circa 1965-1991, Series 5; Box 30: folders 9-72 - Box 34; OP 6, 10-19
  Published material that has been collected by Ormsby is represented in this printed material series, which contains texts by Ormsby, texts about Ormsby's work, and texts by others about various issues of interest to Ormsby. In most cases, descriptions of individually catalogued items refer to the date and source of publication.
  Published works by Ormsby are collected under one subseries divided into subsections for poetry and prose. These documents by Ormsby are arranged alphabetically. Printed material about Ormsby is gathered in a distinct subseries that is further divided into four subsections: one for articles, essays, or other biographical documents about Ormsby as a literary or public figure; one for reviews and clippings about Ormsby's books of poetry; another for reviews and clippings about the books that he has edited; and a fourth for promotional material for his work, including documents relating to readings and lectures.
  Other printed material kept by Ormsby is collected in a third subseries that is also divided into various groups of related materials. This subseries collects a large number of poems, articles, reviews, essays, and stories written by many well-known writers and critics. Apart from the cut-outs, Ormsby also kept various magazines and newspapers in their entirety. An avid theater-goer, Ormsby preserved the playbills of numerous plays performed in Dublin and Belfast theaters from the early 1970's until the 1990's. Most of these programs, however, are from the 1970's. They are largely arranged by theater. Event programs and catalogues from artistic or literary occasions are arranged in yet another subsection.
  Organized into three subseries: (5.1) Printed material by Frank Ormsby, (5.2) Printed material about Frank Ormsby, and (5.3) Other printed material.
  - Printed material by Frank Ormsby, Subseries 5.1; Box 30: folders 9-72; OP 6, 10
    Published texts by Ormsby are grouped as either poetry or prose in this subseries. In many cases, the poems have been simply cut out from newspapers or magazines. On occasion, the removal of individual pieces from the main body of a text has eliminated any record of the source or date of publication.
    Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - Poetry
    - "Apples, Normandy, 1944," in Impartial Republic, 31 October 1985 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - "At Stoke Poges," in The Sunday Times, 7 July 1991 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - "Being Walked by a Dog," in The Irish Press, 29 April 1978 (Box OP10)
    - "A Belfast Journal II," in unknown source (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - "A Belfast Journal V," in unknown source (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - "Bundoran," scrapbook page also includes: "Jim Lyttle's Second-Hand Bookshop," "Kathleen," "Skyhooks," in The Honest Ulsterman, number and date unknown (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - "The Charlotte Gibson Bed," in The Independent, 19 April 1993 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - "The Child," in unknown source (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - "City Buildings," in unknown source (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - "Compromise," [juvenilia] in Arís, St. Michael's College Magazine 1965 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - "The Convoy," in New Statesman, 2 March 1984 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - "Coping," in The Honest Ulsterman No. 35, September / October 1972 (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - "Defense of Poesie," in The Honest Ulsterman, number and date unknown (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - "The Devil's Advocate," in Hibernia, 20 September 1979 (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - "The Diary," in New Statesman, 21/28 December 1984 (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - "Donne," in The Honest Ulsterman, number and date unknown (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - "Dustmen," in unknown source (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - "The Easter Ceasefire," in unknown source (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - "Floods," in The Honest Ulsterman, January - February 1973 (Box 30, Folder 26)
    - "For Matthew," in unknown source (Box 30, Folder 27)
    - "The Gatecrasher," in Ulster News Letter, 15 April 1991 (Box 30, Folder 28)
    - "The Ghost Train," in unknown source (Box 30, Folder 29)
    - "The Goalkeeper," in Ulster News Letter, 18 February 1991 [See also Subseries 3.1c: Poetry by Ormsby (uncollected), "The Goalkeeper"] (Box 30, Folder 30)
    - "High Wind," [See Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby (poetry), "Defense of Poesie"]
    - "The Home Fires," in Gown, 6 May 1976 (Box OP10)
    - "Imaginings," in unknown source (Box 30, Folder 31)
    - "In Memoriam," in The Irish Press, 29 August 1970 [includes: "Fermanagh Landscape," "Labourer," and "In Memoriam"] (Box 30, Folder 32)
    - "In Retrospect," in unknown source [See Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby (poetry), "Sarajevo"]
    - "Inferno: A New Circle," in unknown source (Box 30, Folder 33)
    - "Interior Seasons," in unknown source (Box 30, Folder 34)
    - "Island Honeymoon," in The Irish Press, 7 March 1970 (Box 30, Folder 35)
    - "Islands," in unknown source [See Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby (poetry), "Inferno: A New Circle"]
    - "Jim Lyttle's Second-Hand Bookshop," [See Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby (poetry), "Bundoran"]
    - "Kathleen," in The Honest Ulsterman, January - February 1973 [See Subseries 5.1: Printed material by Ormsby (poetry), "Floods" and "Bundoran"]